A Guide to the Alexandra Ripley Papers, 1977, 1995-1996
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Alexandra Ripley Papers 1977, 1995-1996
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10624-i
This collection consists of 75 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The permission of Alexandra Ripley is required for access to the collection, copying, and all quotations.
Acquisition Information
These papers were loaned to the University of Virginia Library by Alexandra Ripley, Keswick, Virginia, on April 1, 1996.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the papers of Alexandra Ripley, ca. 1990-1994, ca. 75 items (5 Hollinger boxes) consists of research notes, outlines, printed materials, and autograph and typed copies of manuscripts, for Ripley's novel about North Carolina and the tobacco industry, From Fields of Gold, and one electrostatic typescript copy of Scarlett. Also present is a pen and ink drawing titled "Old Mill of Guilford."
Contents List
- AMs From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley, Pages 1-550, with changes & corrections (4 folders) ca. 1992-1993 (Box 1)
- AMs From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley - Miscellaneous Pages, with changes & corrections ca. 1992-1993 (Box 1)
- AMs (EC) From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley, Pages 1-227, with changes & corrections (2 folders) ca. 1992-1993 (Box 1)
- AMs (EC) From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley, Pages 228-274, and Pages 328-374, Second Merrill Draft, with changes & corrections ca. 1992-1993 (Box 2)
- AMs (EC) From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley, Pages 375-550, with changes & corrections (2 folders) ca. 1992-1993 (Box 2)
- AMs & TMs (EC) From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley, Pages 1-141, with changes & corrections ca. 1992-1993 (Box 2)
- TMs (EC) From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley, Pages 142-375, with changes & corrections ca. 1992-1993 (Box 2)
- TMs (EC) From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley, Pages 31-191 ca. 1992-1993 (Box 2)
- TMs (EC) From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley, Pages 192-537 (2 folders) ca. 1992-1993 (Box 3)
- TMs (EC) From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley, Pages 1-535 (3 folders) 1994 Mar (Box 3)
- TMs (EC) From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley, with changes & corrections, Pages 497-576 n.d. (Box 3)
- TMs From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley, Miscellaneous Faxed Pages with Changes & Corrections from Carolyn Blakemore 1994 Mar 22-27 (Box 4)
- From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley - Outlines of the Novel n.d. (Box 4)
- From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley - Research Notes re Tobacco Industry & Several Tobacco Towns 1992-1993 (Box 4)
- From Fields of Gold by Alexandra Ripley - Research Notebooks, including chronology of the book ca. 1993 (Box 4)
- TMs (EC) Scarlett by Alexandra Ripley, Pages 1-1003 (5 folders) ca. 1991 (Box 5)
- Copy of a pen and ink drawing of Old Mill of Guilford1990 Jan 10